Guide to the Records of the Barbara Goldsmith Preservation and Conservation Department RG.38.24
New York University Archives
Records of the Barbara Goldsmith Preservation and Conservation Department
1990-1996, 2004-2021
New York University Archives
New York University. Barbara Goldsmith Preservation and Conservation Department
RG.38.24
13 Linear Feet in 12 boxes.
981.25 Gigabytes in 23,598 computer files
This collection contains the records of the Barbara Goldsmith Preservation and Conservation Department. The mission of the Barbara Goldsmith Preservation Department is to preserve, protect and thereby extend the usable life of the NYU Libraries' collections. The materials concern a variety of preservation and conservation initiatives, including specific grant projects, as well as work involving bindery operations, deacidification programs, preservation microfilming and photocopying projects, preservation supplies, audio/visual preservation, digitization projects, photograph and music research collections, and conservation training. These projects also include efforts to conserve materials held by NYU special repositories.
Conditions Governing Access
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Arrangement
Material in this collection is arranged by general subject/topic and thereunder chronologically. This collection is arranged into thirteen series:
New York State Aid
New York State Aid Projects
Preservation Statistics
American Library Association
Preservation Meetings
Great Collections Microfilming Projects
Archives Preservation Microfilming Project (APMP)
New York State Brittle Books Program (Quality Control Reports)
Bindery
Preservation Supplies
New-York Historical Society
Association of Research Libraries (ARL)
Conservation Documentation
Historical Note
The mission of the Barbara Goldsmith Preservation Department is to preserve, protect and thereby extend the usable life of the NYU Libraries' collections. The department pursues this objective in accordance with the mission and goals of the Libraries, and in conjunction with the University's research mission.
The Preservation Department is responsible for the following activities: commercial binding, conservation treatment, reformatting, disaster preparedness, staff and patron education, and a program to monitor climate control in the Library. In addition, department include programs for moving image and sound preservation, as well as digital conversion. The conservation treatments used in the conservation lab include rebinding, recasing, rebacking, boxing, deacidification, paper cleaning, washing and, mending, as well as other minor repair work in order to preserve collections for current and future scholars. Conservation treatments preserve the physical object through professionally accepted treatments that prolong the life of the materials.
Reformatting techniques are used for books and archive materials that cannot be physically repaired because the paper is too brittle to sustain conservation treatment. These techniques include preservation microfilming and preservation photocopying. In addition, special grant-funded preservation projects are conducted on an ongoing basis within the department to preserve damaged and deteriorating non-book materials, such as, photographs, music scores and audio/visual materials. Moving image and sound preservation are designed to provide collections care, such as proper housing, and reformatting for these rapidly deteriorating collections. The department also administers digital conversion projects that include a preservation component.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was transferred to the University Archives from the Barbara Goldsmith Preservation and Conservation Department. The conservation documention for the years 2004-2009 was transferred to the University Archives from the Conservation Lab in December 2011. An accretion was donated by Lou Di Gennaro in 2019, the accession number associated with this transfer is 2019.096. A further accretion of born-digital files were transferred by Laura McCann in March 2022; the accession number associated with this transfer is 2022.011.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains the records of the Barbara Goldsmith Preservation and Conservation Department from the period 1990-1996, as well as conservation documentation from the period 2004-2009.
The materials concern a variety of preservation and conservation initiatives, including specific grant projects, as well as work involving bindery operations, deacidification programs, preservation microfilming and photocopying projects, and preservation supplies.
Specific preservation projects encompass efforts related to map preservation, student newspapers, a preservation video entitled "Murder in the Stacks," acetate audio recordings, digitization projects, photograph preservation, music research collections, and conservation training. These projects include coordinated programs with other institutions such as Columbia, Cornell and Syracuse Universities, as well as efforts to conserve materials held by NYU special repositories such as Tamiment Library, the Wagner Labor Archives, and Fales Library. The records also document preservation efforts related to the New-York Historical Society library. A significant amount of material deals with the Research Libraries Group (RLG) Great Collections Microfilming Projects (GCMP).
The collection consists of correspondence, grant applications, annual reports, quality control records, meeting records, statistical questionnaires, budgets, expenditure reports, invoices and other financial records. Funding documentation relates primarily to New York State aid, as well as National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) awards. Conference materials cover meetings of the American Library Association (ALA), New York State preservation meetings, and meetings of the Eleven Comprehensive Research Libraries.
In accordance with the American Institute for Conservation (AIC) code of ethics, conservation documentation is maintained in order to establish the condition and aid in the care of cultural property. Conservation documentation relates to treatment of items in the NYU Bobst Special Collections (The Fales Library & Special Collections; Tamiment Library & Wagner Archives; University Archives), the Stephen Chan Library Collection (Institute of Fine Arts), the Ehrman Medical Archives, and the Courant Institute Library.
Conservation documentation consists of logbooks used to track the movement of collection materials in and out of the lab, as well as reports of examination and treatment of items. Some treatment reports include images of the item before, during and after treatment.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Reports.; Memorandums.; Grants.; Financial records; Library materials -- Digitization.; Library materials -- Conservation and restoration; Correspondence.; Libraries -- Special collections.; Books -- Deacidification.; Bindery records.; Preservation microfilming.; Digital images.; Tamiment Library; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives; Elmer Holmes Bobst Library; New-York Historical Society; Research Libraries Group; New York University. Libraries; American Library Association. Annual Conference
- Series I: New York State Aid
  - NY State Grant, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - NY State Grant, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - NY State Grant - Expenditures, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - NY State Grant 5-year plan, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - NY State Grant, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - NY State Grant - Expenditures, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - NY State Grant, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - NY State Grant - Expenditures, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - NY State Grant Annual Report, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - NY State Grant, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - NY State Grant - Expenditures, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - NY State Grant Annual Report, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - NY State Aid Grant, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - NY State Aid Grant - Expenditures, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - NY State Aid Grant - Final Report, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - NY State Aid Grant, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - NY State Aid Grant - Expenditures, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - NY State Aid Grant, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - NY State Aid Grant - Expenditures, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - NY State Aid Grant, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - NY State Aid Grant - Expenditures, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - NY State Aid Grant, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - NY State Aid Grant, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - NY State Aid Grant - Expenditure, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - NY State Aid Grant, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - NY State Aid Grant, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - NY State Aid Grant - Expenditures, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - NY State Aid Grant, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - NY State Aid Grant - Expenditures, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series II: New York State Aid Projects
  - NYS Grant - Coop Program - Maps, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - CUL Videotape, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - NYS Coordinated Preservation Projects, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - NYS Grant - Coop Program Student Newspaper, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Student Newspapers - Expenditures, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - NYS Grant - Coop Program NYS Newspapers, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - NYS Grant - Coordinated Program Acetate Recordings, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - NYS Coordinated Preservation Project, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - NYS Library (Proposed Preservation Activities), 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - NYS Coop Grants Not Funded, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - NYS Coordinated Project Ideas, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - NYS Grant Coordinated Program Conservation Training, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - NYS Coordinated Preservation Projects Application (Hist. Photographic Materials) & NEH applications (178), 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - NYS Coordinated Preservation Projects Application (2nd copy), 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Preservation Photographic Grant Expenditures, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - NYS Coordinated Preservation Projects Final Report, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - NYS Coordinated Preservation Project - Music, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - NYS Music Photocopy Grant - Expenditures, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - NYS Historical Photographic Materials Grant, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - NYS Photography Grant - Expenditures, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - NYS Music Photocopy - Coordinated Grant, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - NYS Music Photocopy Coordinated Grant - Expenditures, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - NYS Tamiment Fiche Project, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - NYS Pamphlet Microfiche Project, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - NYS Coordinated Preservation Projects - Summary of Awards, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - NYS Priorities Survey, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - NYS Serial Symposium, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - NYS Coordinated Preservation Projects - Guidelines and Application, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - NYU Mass Deacidification Seminar - 10/15 & 16, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - NYS Digital Technology Project, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - NYS Discretionary Grant Program, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Fales NEH Proposal, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - NYS Deacidification Project, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - NYS Internship / Travel Expenses, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Greenwich House, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - NYS Digitization Project, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - NYS Coordinated Preservation Projects - Summary of Awards, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - NYS Photo - Letter of Agreement, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - NYS Legislative Issues, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - NYS Isoperms Project, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - NYS Discretionary Grants [1993], 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - NYS Photo Preservation Proposal, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - NYS Science Serials Microfilming Project - SSMP, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - NYS Science Serials Microfilming Project - Science Serial Project, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - NYS Photo Grant, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Digital Training Project, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - NYS Bookkeeper Pilot Project, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - NYS Aid Grant "Use-Based Microfilming Project", 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - NYS Aid Grant "Use-Based Microfilming Project", 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - NYS In-House Treatment & Copy Retention Forms, Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - NYS Budget Modification Instructions/Forms, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Series III: Preservation Statistics
  - Preservation Statistics, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Preservation Statistics, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - NYPL Bindery In-house Statistics, Undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Series IV: American Library Association
  - American Library Association Annual Conference - New Orleans, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - American Library Association Annual Conference - Dallas, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - American Library Association Mid-Winter Meeting - Washington, DC, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - American Library Association Mid-Winter Meeting - Chicago, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - American Library Association Annual Conference - Chicago, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - American Library Association Mid-Winter Meeting - Chicago, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - American Library Association Annual Conference - Atlanta, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - American Library Association Mid-Winter Meeting - San Antonio, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - American Library Association Annual Conference - San Francisco, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - American Library Association Mid-Winter Meeting - Denver, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - American Library Association Annual Conference - New Orleans, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Series V: Preservation Meetings
  - "Our Memory at Risk: Preserving NY's Unique Research Resources" Statewide Conference, May 15, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - NYS Preservation Meeting - Buffalo - Oct. 17-18, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - NYS Cornell Meeting - March 27-28, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - NYS Preservation Committee Meeting - June 4-5, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - NYS Preservation Committee Meeting - Albany - Nov. 13-14, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - NYS Annual Meeting - Cornell, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - NYS Symposium on the Future Role of Big 11 - Sept. 21-23, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - NYS Preservation Program Meeting - New York - June 9-10, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Big 11 Meeting - Albany - Oct. 28, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Big 11 Meeting - Albany - July 23, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Big 11 Meeting - Albany - Oct. 13-14, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Big 11 Meeting - July 20-21, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Big 11 Meeting - Albany - Oct. 18-19, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Big 11 Meeting - Rochester - April 11-12, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Series VI: Great Collections Microfilming Projects
  - Subseries A: Project II (GCMP II)
    - RLG GCMP II Program Managers Meetings, 1989, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - RLG GCMP II Grant Proposal, 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - RLG GCMP II Monthly Reports, 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - RLG GCMP II Quarterly Reports, 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - GCMP II Annual Reports, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - RLG GCMP II Microfilming Contract, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - RLG GCMP II Amended Budget, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - GCMP II Contract Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - GCMP II Methylene Blue Analysis, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Payroll Distribution Statement, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - RLG GCMP II Expenditures, 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - TC Log F0001-F3999 GCMP II (NYU), 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - TC Log F000-F6954 GCMP II (NYU), 1992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Quality Control Log GCMP II (NYU), 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Quality Control Log GCMP II (NYU), 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B: Project IV (GCMP IV)
    - GCMP IV Project Start-up Materials, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - GCMP IV Procedures, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - NEH Applications [29 May 1992], 1993-1996 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - GCMP IV Expenditures, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - GCMP IV Quarterly Reports, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - MAPS/Preservation Resources Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - National Underground Storage Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Project Staff Memorandum, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - GCMP IV Worksheets, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - RLG/GCMP IV Quality Control Reports (Filming Agent), 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - RLG/GCMP IV Quality Control Reports (NYU), 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - GCMP IV Quality Control Reports (Filming Agent), 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - GCMP IV Quality Control Log (Filming Agent), 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - GCMP IV Title Control Log (NYU), 1993-1995 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Series VII: Archives Preservation Microfilming Project (APMP)
  - Archives' RLG RFP, 1985-1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - RLG Archives Preservation Microfilming Project, 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - JLC Finding Aid and Inventory, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - APMP Contract, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - RLG Archives Microfilming Training Session - May 1-2, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - RLG APMP NEH Application (1989), 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - RLG APMP Monthly & Quarterly Reports, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - RLG APMP Project Managers Meeting - June 3, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - RLG APMP Quality Control Records, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - RLG APMP Project Managers Meeting - June 8, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - RLG APMP Cost Study, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - RLG APMP Expenditures, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - RLG APMP Needs Assessment (Archives/Preservation), 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - RLG APMP Materials for Manual, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Series VIII: New York State Brittle Books Program (Quality Control Reports)
  - 2157-2171, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 8208-8250, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 8251-8299, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 8300-8331, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 8460-8499, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 8754-8799, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 8800-8850, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 8851-8875, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 8876-8899, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 8900-8950, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 8951-8975, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 8976-8999, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Series IX: Bindery
  - Bindery Workflow (organization of), 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bindery Supplies (start-up), 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bindery Budget & Record, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Commercial Binderies, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Commercial Binding Invoices, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Book Lab, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Series X: Preservation Supplies
  - Preservation Supplies, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Preservation Supplies, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Series XI: New-York Historical Society
  - New-York Historical Society Library Preservation Plan, 1989-1994 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - New-York Historical Society Annual Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - New-York Historical Society RAP NEH Project, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - New-York Historical Society - NYU Agreement, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - New-York Historical Society Collection Meeting, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - New-York Historical Society Mold Outbreak, April, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - New-York Historical Society Discretionary Grant (Manuscript Survey)(1), 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - New-York Historical Society Discretionary Grant (Manuscript Survey)(2), 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - New-York Historical Society NEH MAP Project (1), 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - New-York Historical Society NEH MAP Project (2), 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Series XII: Association of Research Libraries (ARL)
  Scope and Content Note
  ARL preservation statistics are missing for the years 1985-1986 and 1986-1987.
  - ARL Preservation Statistics, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - ARL Preservation Statistics, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - ARL Preservation Statistics, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - ARL Preservation Statistics, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - ARL Preservation Statistics, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - ARL Preservation Statistics, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - ARL Preservation Statistics, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - ARL Preservation Statistics, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - ARL Preservation Statistics, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - ARL Preservation Statistics, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 20)